<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Blog | Timeu's Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://timeu.github.io/blog/categories/blog/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://timeu.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-02-18T17:30:57+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://timeu.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Ümit Seren]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hello World]]></title>
    <link href="http://timeu.github.io/blog/2014/02/18/hello-world/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-18T14:44:21+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://timeu.github.io/blog/2014/02/18/hello-world</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I have been playing with the idea of starting to blog for a while now, however I always ended up putting it off because there were other more &ldquo;important&rdquo; things to do. Now that I have a little bit time on my hand I decided to stop procastinating and start blogging.</p>

<!--more -->


<p>My goal with this blog is to share my knwoledge regarding web-technologies and applications in the scientific field (my current field of expertise). I will blog about the various projects I work on, the technologies that underly them and the challenges I encounter and if possible provide solutions I came up with.</p>

<p>I enjoy reading blogs about various interesting topics in the field of web-technologies. It is inspirational to see how people approach problems and try to develop solutions. This is an invaluable source of knowledge and has often saved me a lot of time when dealing with similar problems. I hope I can also give some of my knowledge back to the community.</p>

<p>However I didn&rsquo;t start this blog only out of altruistic motives but also as a way to keep track of the work I have been doing.
Of course a blog is much more than just documentation of some code I wrote, so I will try hard to keep the blog posts condensed, strucuted and intersting for readers. I guess this is easier said than done.</p>

<h1>Hi @ Octopress</h1>


<p>Surround your pullquote like this {" text to be quoted "}</p>

<p>After Googling various solutions I stumbled over <a href="http://staticgen.com/">Static Site Generators</a>. The most popular ones seem to be <a href="http://jekyllrb.com/">Jekyll</a>, <a href="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</a> and <a href="http://middlemanapp.com/">Middleman</a>. I am not really experienced in Ruby but they all seem to be quite straightforward to use.</p>

<p>A big advantage of using a static site generator is that I can use <a href="http://pages.github.com/">Github Pages</a> for hosting my blog (Github has built-in support for Jekyll) and as most of my projects are hosted on <a href="http://github.com/timeu">Github</a> anyways this seems to be a natural fit.</p>

<p>I decided to go with Octopress which uses Jekyll under the hood but I didn&rsquo;t really like their default theme. I was looking for a minimalistic whitespace theme. After some research I discovered Vladi Gleba`s beautiful <a href="https://github.com/vladigleba/readify">Readify</a> theme and I was quickly sold. It&rsquo;s a great minimalistic responsive Octopress theme that focuses on readibility and that&rsquo;s the theme I am using now.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
